Nikhil Nandkumar Waykos

Contact No.: +91 9511664263 | Email: nikhil.waykos@gmail.com | Address: Aurangabad, MH, India.

Website: aminikhil.github.io | LinkedIn: in.linkedin.com/in/nikhil-waykos-083610146 | GitHub: github.com/aminikhil

Summary

Full Stack Developer with expertise in React, Angular, SQL, NoSQL, Node.js, Express.js, Spring Boot and Google Cloud Platform with 1 year and 9 months experience. I am seeking an opportunity for a Software Developer position in a growth-oriented company where I can utilize my skills and knowledge of Application Development in the maximum possible ways.

Work Experience

Full Stack Developer - Deskera Systems India

Dec 2022 - Present

- Debugging/developing front-end application in React and Angular framework.
- Debugging/developing back-end application in Spring Boot and Node.js technology.
- Working on micro-services architecture

Software Development Engineer In Test - Amdocs India

Jul 2021 - Dec 2022

- Developing automation test scripts and improving performance with Python and Ginger Automation Tool.
- Designing test cases, performing testing for telecommunication BSS Applications CRM, Web Applications,
 Ordering Management System, Event Processing, Master Enterprise Catalog, and Ensemble Billing.

Internships

Full Stack Developer Intern – Teckytrick Consultancy Services

Feb 2021 - Jul 2021

- Developed E2E Web Applications using React and state management tools like Redux and Redux Saga.
- Developed Mobile Application using Android Native (Kotlin) with popular Jetpack libraries.
- Developed REST API using Node.js and Express.js with Firestore NoSQL Database and deployed on Google Cloud App Engine.

Projects

E-Commerce Platform

- An e-commerce platform for connecting wholesalers and retailers across pan India.
- Developed Admin & Wholesalers application in React and state management tools like Redux and Redux Saga.
- Developed REST API using Express.js with Firestore NoSQL database and deployed on Google App Engine.
- Developed auto-triggered Firebase Cloud Functions (Serverless Application).

Covid-19 Patients' Report Tracking

- Platform for Doctors to daily monitor home quarantine patients' health with details of their oxygen level, temperature, and pulse rate.
- Developed a progressive web app in React and state management tools like Redux and Redux Saga.
- Used user authentication and authorization Firebase Auth service, Firestore NoSQL database.

Education

B.Tech. Computer Science & Engineering (GPA 9.1)
CSMSS Chh. Shahu College of Engineering, Aurangabad

June 2021

Skills

- Expert in React, Angular and Android Native (Kotlin) Application Development
- Expert in Node.js, Express.js, Spring Boot Backend Application Development
- Experienced with SQL and NoSQL Databases MySQL, MongoDB, Firestore
- Experienced with Firebase, Google Cloud Platform (GCP), IBM Cloud
- Developed applications in Java, JavaScript, Python, Kotlin, and C++ languages

Certifications

•	IBM Full Stack Software Developer Professional Certificate	2022
•	NPTEL Cloud Computing	2020
•	REDHAT RHCSA	2019
•	NPTEL Database Management System	2019